<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Jasmeet Singh</title><link>https://localhost:1313/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Jasmeet Singh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>jasmeet0915@gmail.com (Jasmeet Singh)</managingEditor><webMaster>jasmeet0915@gmail.com (Jasmeet Singh)</webMaster><copyright>Copyright © 2025 Jasmeet Singh</copyright><atom:link href="https://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Functional Weeder</title><link>https://localhost:1313/projects/functional-weeder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jasmeet0915@gmail.com (Jasmeet Singh)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/projects/functional-weeder/</guid><description>Built a fleet of two line-following robots with custom 3D-printed pick-and-place mechanisms during the e-Yantra Robotics Competition 2021–22. Developed algorithms for grid-based path planning, mapping, fleet management, PID-based line following and manipulation in Elixir. Selected among the top 5 teams out of nearly 300.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://localhost:1313/projects/functional-weeder/featured.jpg"/></item><item><title>S.T.A.R: Satellite Trajectory Animating &amp; Rendering</title><link>https://localhost:1313/projects/star/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jasmeet0915@gmail.com (Jasmeet Singh)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/projects/star/</guid><description>A fun project with a fusion of art and engineering — simulated the trajectories of 300+ Starlink satellites in Blender using orbital mechanics and particle systems. The goal was to make scientifically accurate but cool looking simulations. The project trended on the official Starlink subreddit and drew interest from SpaceX engineers for potential collaboration.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://localhost:1313/projects/star/featured.gif"/></item><item><title>S.T.E.W.A.R.D: Smart TErrestrial WArehouse Robot Deployment</title><link>https://localhost:1313/projects/steward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jasmeet0915@gmail.com (Jasmeet Singh)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/projects/steward/</guid><description>First prize winning project for Mitsubishi America&amp;rsquo;s Rally-To-Tally Online Hackathon. Developed an autonomous solution for their problem statement of inventory management of large industrial steel pipes using computer vision and outdoor mobile robots. Demostrated the PoC with the help of a custom simulation of Husky robot in Gazebo with InfluxDB and Grafana for integration for the data visualization</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://localhost:1313/projects/steward/featured.jpg"/></item><item><title>ROS Perception Pipeline</title><link>https://localhost:1313/projects/perception-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jasmeet0915@gmail.com (Jasmeet Singh)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/projects/perception-pipeline/</guid><description>An open source project being developed as part of A.T.O.M Robotics Lab. The project is intended to work as a one-stop solution for easily deploying perception pipelines with common applications like object detection, image segmentation, image pre processing, etc. The project follows modular plugin-based architecture much like Nav2 in concept. The project is actively used in A.T.O.M&amp;rsquo;s in-house mobile robot - MR Robot</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://localhost:1313/projects/perception-pipeline/featured.gif"/></item><item><title>Real Harry Potter Wand using Computer Vision</title><link>https://localhost:1313/projects/real-harry-potter-wand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jasmeet0915@gmail.com (Jasmeet Singh)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/projects/real-harry-potter-wand/</guid><description>The first project I made in college that got me into Computer Vision and Machine Learning. By tracking the end of a retroreflector-tipped harry potter wand replica and training my own SVM for handwritten character recognition, I was able to do magic in real life. This was demostrated by the spell Alohomora that opens a box when you write &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; in mid-air using the wand. The project got featured in official blogs at Raspberry Pi, Hackaday and a complete article in the 86th issue of MagPi, the official Raspberry Pi magazine</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://localhost:1313/projects/real-harry-potter-wand/featured.jpg"/></item><item><title>LED Coffee Table</title><link>https://localhost:1313/projects/led-coffee-table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jasmeet0915@gmail.com (Jasmeet Singh)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/projects/led-coffee-table/</guid><description>Made in collaboration with the Hatchnhack Makerspace in Delhi, we made a complete coffe table with a 12x12 LED Matrix inside for playing interactiveness and cool animations. The project used WS2812B LEDs with an ESP32 Dev Board at the heart for the controls</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://localhost:1313/projects/led-coffee-table/featured.gif"/></item><item><title>MR (ModulaR) Robot</title><link>https://localhost:1313/projects/mr-robot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jasmeet0915@gmail.com (Jasmeet Singh)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/projects/mr-robot/</guid><description>Our in-house custom designed and fabricated AMR at A.T.O.M. The hardware and software design follows a modular architecture making this fitting for the multiple applications, hence the name MR (ModulaR) Robot.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://localhost:1313/projects/mr-robot/featured.jpg"/></item><item><title>Sahayak Bot</title><link>https://localhost:1313/projects/sahayak-bot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jasmeet0915@gmail.com (Jasmeet Singh)</author><guid>https://localhost:1313/projects/sahayak-bot/</guid><description>Made during the e-yantra Robotics Competition 2020-21, Sahayak Bot was the first project that introduced me to simulation-based advanced robotics development using ROS &amp;amp; Gazebo. We focused on the developement of the autonomy stack of Sahayak Bot, a mobile manipulator, including navigation, SLAM, perception, manipulation &amp;amp; mission planning using ROS, Gazebo and Moveit!. Upon completition our implementation was selected among top 7 finalists out of almost 500 teams.</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://localhost:1313/projects/sahayak-bot/featured.png"/></item></channel></rss>